Henry Y. Porter Theater Memorabilia Collection MS003
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Henry Y. Porter Theater Memorabilia Collection
1890 -- 1950
1722 -- 1999
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Porter, Henry Y.
MS003
59.95 Linear Feet
4 Volumes
4 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into six series: Artists and other celebrities; Olive Fremstad; Scrapbooks, playbills, and programs; Obituary scrapbooks; Phonograph recordings; Political, military, and judicial figures.
Biographical / Historical
Henry Y. Porter (c.1890-c.1950) was employed by Tufts University as an accountant for many years. He was an active collector of theater, opera, and political memorabilia and portraits.
Custodial History
This collection was given to Tufts in 1986 by Porter's estate.
Scope and Contents
The collection is composed of photographs, scrapbooks, cartes de visite, and cabinet card photo album depicting various theater and musical personalities primarily from the 19th and early 20th centuries. Also included are photographs, prints, and clippings of various political, military, and judicial figures, from the 1800s to the 1980s. There are an estimated 10,000 images. The primary focus of the collection is people involved in music, theater, opera, and government.
Porter classified the bulk of the photos by subject and date, and includes handwritten tables of contents for many of the albums. Additionally, there are scrapbooks of obituaries of people represented in the collection.
Porter purchased much of the material from antiques dealers and from auctions.
Opera.; Actors; Theater; Public officers; Greater Boston arts
- Artists and other celebrities; prints, photographs, and artifacts, 1722 -- 1990; 1880 -- 1920; MS003.001; 33.95 Linear Feet; 1 Volumes; 4 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photographic images including cabinet cards, cartes de visite, 8x10s, 5x7s as well as a selection of etchings, engravings and lithographs. The cabinet cards include actors, actresses, opera singers and musicians signed and unsigned ranging primarily from 1880-1910. The cabinet cards include over 800 different actors, actresses and other entertainment personalities such as Maude Adams, Elizabeth Clark, Pauline Hall, Julia Marlowe, Edwin Booth, Benoit-Constant Coquelin, and Richard Mansfield. Musical performers from the late 19th century are also included such as Jesse Bartlett-Davies, Agnes Huntington, Adelina Patti and Cyril Tyler. There are a substantial amount of mid twentieth-century celebrity 8x10s including a large number of operatic personalities. There also includes a number of oversized opera posters and large card sized images, many of them signed. The etchings and prints are primarily from the 1800's. They include images of famous actors and performers in their specialty roles such as Charlotte Cushman, E.L. Davenport, Edwin Booth et al., mostly taken from older collector series books. The cartes de visite are mostly unorganized and include theatrical, musical and cultural personalities from the mid to late nineteenth century. Some artifacts are included as well, a one-of-a kind Jenny Lind empire clock given to P.T. Barnum, two small busts of Enrico Caruso, and some unidentified costume items.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by material type.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, A, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.001.001 (Box 1)
    Photographs are arranged alphabetically.
    Adams, Margaret; Adams, Maude; Aimee, Marie; Akerstrom, Ullie; Allan, ?; Allan, Viola; Alter, Lottie; Alphabet, Madge; Anderson, Mary; Angelin, Margaret; Angell, Milly; Archer, Belle; Arthur, Julia; Ashley, Minnie; Asterman, Kathryn; Atherton, Alice
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, B, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.002.001 (Box 2)
    Baker, Josephine; Bandmann, Millicent; Barry, Clara; Barrymore, Ethel; Barrymore, Georgie Drew; Bartel, Mme; Batchelder, Fannie; Bates, Blanche; Batting, Ethel Munro; Beaudet, Louise; Beaudet, Rose; Beebe, Mary; Beecher, Rosalba; Bell, Ida; Bell, Laura Joyce; "Bella"; Belmont, Frances; Bender, Blanche; Bennett, Johnstone; Bentley, Irene; Bentley, Mollie; Bergere, Valerie; Bernard-Beere, Fanny; Bernhardt, Sarah; Berolde, Judith; Bertram, Helen; Bingham, Ameila; Bionda, Marguerite; Blair, Eugenie; Blanchard, Kitty; Blancke, Annie; Blande, Edith; Blocke, Adele; Bloodgood, Fanny; Bloodgood, Clara; Blow, Lillia; Bond, Jessie; Boote, Rosie; Booth, Agnes; Booth, Hope; Booth, Rachel; Boucicault, Mme; Bowers, Mrs. D.P.; Boyd, Anna; Bradley, Leonora; Braggins, Nellie; Branscombe, Maude; Briscoe, Lottie; Brune, Minnie Tittell; Brooklyn, May; Burke, Bille; Burkhart, Lillian; Burress, Marie; Burroughs, Marie; Burt, Laura; Busby, Amy; Busley, Jessie; Butler, Nellie; Byron, Helen
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, C, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.003.001 (Box 3)
    Cahill, Marie; Caine, Georgia; Calef, Jennie; Cameron, Beatrice; Cameron, Violet; Campbell, Evelyn; Campbell, Fauchon; Campbell, Mrs. Patrick; Carew, ?; Carle, Alice; "Carmencita"; Carter, Mrs. Leslie; Castleton, Kate; Cavendish, Ada; Cayvan, Georgia; Celeste, Marie; Chanfrau, Henrietta; "Charmion"; Cheatham, Kitty; Chester, Dorothy; Claire, Attalie; Clancey, Venie; Clanse, Mrs. ?; Clarke, Annie; Clark, Elizabeth; Clark, Hilda; Clark, Maybel; Claxton, Kate; Clayton, Bessie; Clayton, Estelle; Clemmons, Katherine; Cleveland, Bessie; Cline, Maggie; Coghlan, Gertrude; Coghlan, Rose; Cohan, Josephine; Colemons, Florence (?); Collier, Lizzie Hudson; Collier, Louise Allan; Collins, Lottie; Conalba, Mlle.; Conquest, Ida; Conway, Minnie; Conway, Lillian; Coombs, Jane; Corden, Juliette; Comstock, Nannette; "Corrine"; Courtenay, Vera; Couthoui, Jessie; Cowell, Sydney; Crabtree, Lotta; Craigen, Maida; Crane, Edith; Crater, Allene; Craven, Margaret; Creighton, Bertha; Crosman, Henrietta; Crox, Elvia; Cushman, Adilaid; Cushman, Charlotte; Cyr, Antoinette
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, D-F, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.004.001 (Box 4)
    Dale, Margaret; Daly, Lucy; Daly, Margaret; D'Arville, Camille; Dauvray, Helen; Davenport, Fanny (Jr.); Davenport, Fanny (Sr.); Davenport, May (sister); Davis, Fay; Davis, Phoebe; Davies, H. Rees; Dayne, Helen; Dellenbaugh, Harriet Otis; DeMar, Carrie; DeMerode, Cleo; Dene, Dorothy; Denin-Wilson, Kate; DeWolfe, Elsie; Diard, Fatmah; Dickson, Georgia; Dietz, Linda; Dillon, Louise; Don, Laura; Donnelly, Dorothy; Dore, Ada; Dore, Annie; Dore, Jane; Dore, Marie; Dow, Anne G.; Dreher, Virginia; Dresser, Marcia van; Dressler, Marie; Drew, Dorothy; Drew, Louise; Drew, Gladys; Duffies, Blanche; Dupre, Minnie; Durbin, Maud; Duse, Elenora; Dutillay, Mme.; Dyas, Ada; Earle, Virginia; Eastlake, Mary; Eaton, Mabel; Ediss, Connie; Edmonson, Janet; Edwardes, Paula; Eilson, Elain; Eldridge, Louise; Elliott, Gertrude; Elliott, Maxine; Elliston, Grace; Ellsler, Effie; Emmerson, Adelaide; Emmons, Sadie; Ethel, Agnes; Evans, Agnes; Evesson, Isabelle; Eytinge, Pearl; Eytinge, Rose; "Fanchonnette"; Farrell, Leila; Farren, Nellie; Farrington, Nina; Faust, Lotta; Fealy, Maude; Felix, Eliza; Fenton, Mabel; Fernandez, Bijou; Filkins, Grace; Fischer, Alice; Fiske, Minnie Maddern; Fitzallen, A.; Fitzgerald, Cissy; Fitzsimmons, Mrs. Robert; Florence, Katherine; Florence, Melvina Pray; Forsythe, Kate; Fortescue, May; Fougere, Eugenie; Fox, Della; Fox, Nellie; Freeman, Grace; Friganza, Trixie; Funsh, Minnie (?); Fuller, Margaret; Fuller, Loie; Fuller, Molly
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, G-I, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.005.001 (Box 5)
    Gale, Minna K.; Galland, Bertha; Gallatin, Alberta; Gehrue, Maynie; Geoffrey, Mrs. ?; George, Grace; Germaine, Katherine; Germon, Effie; Gerrish, Sylvia; Gilbert, Mrs. G. H. (Haitley); Gillette, Fanny; Gilly, Mme (?); Gilman, Ada; Gilman, Maybel; Gilroy, Mamie; Gilson, Lottie; Girard, Florence; Glaser, Lulu; Glover, Amelia; Golden, Grace; Goldthwaite, Jennie; Gordon, Caroline; Gould, Edith Kingdom; Grace, Sarah; Granger, Maude; Greenwood, Grace; Grey, Catherine; Guilbert, Yvette; "Guerrero"; Hading, Jane; Hall, Isobel; Hall, Josephine; Hall, Marguerette; Hall, Maud Edna; Hall, Pauline; Halton, Marie; Hampton, Mary; Harlow, R.; Harned, Virginia; Harold, Lizzie; Harper, Belle; Harrison, Maud; Hart, Kate; Harvey, Hattie; Haskins, Isabel; Haslam, Maud; Haswell, Percy; Held, Anna; Hellar, Miss ?; Helstone, Mrs.; Henderson, Grace; Herndon, Agnes; Herne, Chrystal; Herne, Julie; Herne, Katherine C.; Heron, Bijou; Herring, Fanny; Hill, Lucile; Hilton, Marie; Hoffman, Maud; Hoffs, Violet; Holland, Kate; Holland, Mildred; Hopper, Edna Wallace; Hosford, Maud; Howard, Nellie; Howland, Jobyna; Howson, Emma; Hughs, Jennie; Illington, Margaret; Irving, Isabell; Irwin, Flora; Irwin, May
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, J-L, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.006.001 (Box 6)
    James, Millie; Janauschek, Fanny; Janis, Elsie; Jansen, Marie; Jarbeau, Verona; Jeffries, Maud; Jewel, Izetta; Jewett, Sara; Johnson, Selene; Johnstone, Fanny; Joyce, Jennie; Judic, Anna; Kahn, Florence; Kalich, Bertha; Keim, Adelaide; Kemble, Charles; Kendal, Madge Robertson; Kendall, Mrs. W.H.; Kennark, Jane; Kidder, Katheryn; Kimball, Grace; Kingdon, Edith; Kiralfy, Haniola (?); Knott, Clara; Knott, Roselle; Langtry, Lily; Laughlin, Anna; LaVerne, Lucille; Lawrence, Lillian; Leclercq, Carlotta; Leigh, Lisle; LeMoyne, Sara Cowell; Leslie, Annie; Leslie, Cora; Leslie, Elsie; Lessing, Madge; Lewis, Ada; Lewis, Catherine; Lewis, Jeffries; Lewis, Lillian; Lind, Letty; Lingard, Alice; Lingard, Catherine; Lingard, Dickey; Linthicum, Lotta; Lipman, Clara; Loftus, Cecilia "Cissy"; Ludic, Josie; Lynch, Nellie; Lynton, Ethel
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, M-O, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.007.001 (Box 7)
    MacDonald, Christie; MacNichol, Lizzie; Majilton, Marie; Mannering, Mary; Manola, Marion; Mansfield, Josie; Markham, Pauline; Marlowe, Julia; Martinot, Sadie; Massey, Rose; Masterton, Lilian (?); Mather, Margaret; Maveroffer, Amelia (?); May, Edna; May, Olive; Mayo, Eleanor; McCall, Lizzie; McHenry, Nellie; McIntosh, Nancy; McIntyre, Fanny; Meek, Kate; Melville, Rose; Mendum, Georgie; Miliken, Sandel (?); Millcitt, Maybel (?); Millword, Jessie; Miskel-Hoyt, Caroline; Mitchell, Maggie; Modjeska, Helen; Montague, Louise; Moore, Ethel; Morant, Fanny; Morin, Pilar; Morgan, Maud; Moretti, Eleanor; Morris, Clara; Morris, Florence Wood; Mulle, Ida; Murdoch, Daisy; Myrs, Emma; Naughton, Theresa; Neilson, Adelaide; Neilson, Julia; Nesbit, Evelyn; Nethersole, Olga; Noah, Rachel; Nobles, Dolly; Oates, Alice; Odell, Maude; Oesterle, Kate; O'Keefe, Annie; O'Leary, Miriam; O'Neill, Anne; O'Neill, Nance; Opp, Julie; Osborne, Maud; Osborne, Merri; Osterman, Kathryn; Otero, Caroline; Otis, Elita Proctor; "Little Ollie"
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, P-R, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.008.001 (Box 8)
    Paget, Folliot; Palliser, Esther; Palmer, Adele; Palmer, Minnie; Paullin, Louise; Peters, Mrs. Charles; Pixley, Annie; Potter, Cora Urquhart; Prescott, Marie; Prince, Adelaide; Rafler, Adele; Rand, Olivia; Rankin, Mrs. McKee; Rankin, Phyllis; Rankin, Gladys; Rawinson, Grace; Rawlinson, Zelma; Raymond, Alice; Redmond, Helen; Rehan, Ada; Reignolds, Kate; Rejane, Gabrielle; Rhea, Hortense; Riccardo, Corona; Ricci, Bertha; Rice, Fanny; Richmond, Mrs. ?; Richmond-Stitson, Adah; Rigl, Emily; Ristori, Adelaide; Ritchie, Adele; Robe, Annie; Robson, Eleanor; Robson, May; Rockwell, Florence; Rolla, Kate; Rooner, Katie; Roosevelt, Blanche; Rorke, Kate; Rosa, Patty; Rosell, Amy; Rousby, Clara; Rujaevo, Esther (?); Rush, Isadore; Russell, Annie; Russell, Hattie; Russell, Lillian; Ryan, Kate; Ryan, Elsie
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, S-T, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.009.001 (Box 9)
    Sachlia (?); Sadler, Josie; Sanders, Mary; Sanderson, Julia; Sanson, Bessie; Santley, Kate; Satterlee, Jennie; Savio, Filomena; Second-Weber, Eugenie; Seligman, Minnie; Selwyn, Ethel; Shannon, Effie; Shaw, Mary; Sheridan, Emma V.; Shotwell, Marie; Siddons, Marie (Scott); Sitgreaves, Beverly; Skipworth, Allison; Slack, Anna; Smith, Sol; Solderne, Emily; Spong, Hilda; Spooner, Cecil; Spooner, Edna May; Stacey, Delia; Stanley, Alma Stuart; Stannard, Anna; Starr, Frances; St. Claire, Edith; Steintright (?); Stevens, Sara; St. Henry, Jeanette; Stone, Marie; Stokes, Kate; Strebal, Marie; Stuart, Jane; Studholme, Marie; Summerville, Amelia; Sutherland, Annie; Swindelhurst, Lillian; Syres, Alma; Taliaferro, Mabel; Tanner, Cora; Tavary, Marie; Taylor, Laurette; Tealy, Maude; Tempest, Marie; Templeton, Fay; TenBroeck, May; Tennant, Dorothy; Terris, Ellaline; Terry, Ellen; Terry, Marium and Florence; Theadore, Gladys (baby); Thompson, Lydia; Thorne, Nellie; Thorne, Sylvia; Tiffany, Annie Ward; Truax, Sarah; Tyler, Odette; Tyree, Elizabeth (Bessie); Tyrell, Anne
  - Cabinet cards, actresses, U-Z, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.010.001 (Box 10)
    Ulmer, Geraldine; Urquhart, Isabelle; Valli Valli; Vassar, Queenie; Vanoni, Marie; Varian, Nina; Vaughn, Kate; Vaughn, Theresa; Vernon, Harriettt; Vernon, Ida; Verona, Irene; Vesey, Clara; Vickers, Mattie; Victoria, Vesta; Vincent, Ethel; Vincent, Helen; Vincent, Mary Ann; Vincent, Ruth; Violette, Yvette; Vokes, Margaret Daly; Vokes, May; Vokes, Rosina; Vokes, Victoria; Vokes Family; Wainwright, Marie; Walker, Charlotte; Wallace, Yolande; Wallis, Gladys; Walsh, Blanche; Ward, Fannie; Warrillow, Maude; Weathersby, Eliza; Weathersby, Jennie; Webster, Lizzie; West, Floren; Whalley, Norma; Wheatcroft, Adeline; Wheeler, Bernica; Whiffen, Blanche; Wilkins, Marie; Williams, Mrs. Barney; Williams, Hattie; Williams, Marie; Wilson, Julia; WInston, Jennie; Wood, Mrs. John; Wood, Rose; Yeamans, Lydia; Yearance, Ida; Yohe, May; Young, Mary; Zabelle, Flora
  - Cabinet cards, actors, A-C, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.011.001 (Box 11)
    Abeles, Edward S.; Adams, Edwin; Allen, Leslie; Amberg, Gustave; Arbuckle, Maclyn; Arden, Edwin; Arliss, George; Backus, Eben Young (E.Y.); Bangs, Frank C.; Barnes, J. H.; Barrett, Lawrence; Barrett, WIlson; Barron, Charles; Barrymore, Maurice; Bassermann, Adolf (?); Beach, William; Beckman, DeJose; Belasco, David; Bell, Charles, J.; Bell, Digby V.; Bellow, Kyrle; Belmore, George; Bennett, Richard; Bentley, Walter; Bergman, Henry; Bernard, Sam; Biorksten, Theo; Birch, Billy; Bispham, David; Boniface, George C., Jr.; Boniface, George C., Sr.; Booth, Edwin; Booth, John WIlkes; Bosworth, Hobart; Boucicault, Aubrey; Boucicault, Dion; Bourchier, Arthur; Boyne, Leonard; Bradshaw, Charles; Brantford, WIll; Buhler, Richard; Burgess, Neil; Burroughs, Claude; Byron, Arthur; Caine, Hall; Calvert, Charles; Carroll, J. W. (?); Cherry, Charles; Clayton, Henry; Clement, Clay; Coghlan, Charles; Cohen, J. H.; Coleman, Thomas L.; Coles, Chas.; Collier, William; Compton, Edward; Conor, Harry; Cook, Augustus; Coquelin, Benoit-Constant; Countenay, William; Courtleigh, William; Couldock, Charles W.; Coulter, Frazu; Cowper, John C.; Coyne, Joseph; Craig, John; Crane, WIlliam H.; Craven, John; Crisp, Harry; Crompton, William H.
  - Cabinet cards, actors, D-G, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.012.001 (Box 12)
    Dacre, Arthur; Dailey, Peter; Dalton, Charles; Daly, Arnold; Daniels, Frank; Davenport, Edgar; Davenport, Edward L.; Davenport, Harry; Davidge, William, Jr.; Davidge, William, Sr.; Davis, Richard Harding; De Angelis, Jefferson; De Belleville, Frederic; Decone, M.; Delmore, Ralph; Dickson, Charles; Dodson, John E.; Dorsay, Lawrence; Drew, John; Drouet, Robert; Duquesne, Edmond; Earfield, Eugene (?); Eddinger, Wallace (Wallie); Edeson, Robert; Edgett, E. F.; Emerson, Billy; Emmet, J. K.; Etting, Henry; Evans, Charles; Falkland, Arthur; Farkoa, Maurice; Farnum, William; Faversham, William; Fawcett, Owen; Fechter, Charles; Ferguson, William; Fisher, Charles; Fitch, Clyde; Fitzbattleaxe, Captain (?); Florence, W. J.; Forrest, Arthur; Forrest, Edwin; Foy, Eddie; Gentry, James B.; Gilbert, John; Gilfoil, Harry (?); Gillette, William; Gilmore, Barney; Gilmore, Frank; Gilmore, Paul; Gilmour, John H.; Girard, Joseph W.; Girardot, Etienne; Glazier, Harry A.; Golden, Richard; Goodwin, Nat C.; Gottschalk, Ferdinand; Gould, Howard; Grandin, Elmer; Grapewin, Charles; Griffith, Frank C.; Grismen, Joseph; Grossmith, George, Jr.
  - Cabinet cards, actors, H-L, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.013.001 (Box 13)
    Hackett, James; Hampden, Walter; Hardenbergh, Frank (?); Hare, John; Harkins, Daniel; Harlan, Otis; Harper, E. R. (Ned); Harrigan, Edward; Harrison, Gabriel; Hart, William A.; Hastings, Cuyler; Hawarth, Joseph; Hawtry, Sir Charles; Herbert, J. W.; Herne, James A.; Hicks, Seymour; Hilliard, Robert C.; Hodge, William; Holland, Edmund; Holland, George L.; Holland, Joseph; Hopper, De Wolf; Hudson, William; Ingersoll, William; Irving, Sir Henry; Irving, Laurence; Jackson, Charles; James, Louis; Jefferson, Joseph; Jefferson, Thomas; Jefferson, William; Jeffries, Joseph; Jennings, John W.; Jewett, Henry; Johnson, Tefft; Jones, Walter; Karl, Tom; Keating, M. J.; Keene, Thomas; Keith, B. F.; Kellar, Harry; Kelcey, Herbert; Kendall, Ezra; Kendal, William H.; Kent, Charles; Kilgour, Joseph; Kroeger, Ernest R.; Lackaye, James; Lackaye, WIlton; Levick, Gus; Lewis, Horace; Lewis, James; Lockhart, Sam; Losee, Frank; Lunt, Alfred; Lytell, Bert
  - Cabinet cards, actors, M-R, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.014.001 (Box 14)
    MacDonald, William; MacDonough, Harry; MacDowell, Melbourne; Mack, Andrew; MacKay, F. F.; Maguinis, Dan; Mann, Louis; Mansfield, Richard; Mantell, Robert; Marlowe, Owen; Marshall, Wyzerman; Mason, John; Massen, Louis; Massett, Steve; Mathews, J. Sherrie; Maude, Cyril; Mayo, Frank; McAvoy, Dan; McClannin, Robert; McCullough, John; McGlenen, H. A. M.; McIntosh, Burr; McRae, Bruce; McSarty, L. J. (?); Mestayer, W. A.; Miller, Henry; Montague, Harry J.; Montgomery, Dave; Moody, W. R.; Mordant, Edwin; Mordaunt, Frank; Morgan, Edward J.; Morris, Felix; Morris, William; Morrison, Lewis; Mostyn, Haller; Mounet-Sully, Jean; Murdoch, James; Murdock, Harry; Neville, Henry; Nobles, Milton; Norris, William; Novelli, Ernete; Olcott, Chauncey; O'Neill, James; Palmer, Albert; Parselle, John; Pastor, Tony; Paulding, Frederick; Pauncefort, George; Payne, John Howard; Pitt, Henry M.; Placide, Henry; Pounds, Courtize; Power, Tyrone; Power, James T.; Pruette, William; Ramsey (?); Rankin, A. McKee; Ratcliffe, Edward J.; Redmund, WIlliam; Reed, Roland; Reid, Hal; Richardson, George; Richman, Charles; Riddle, George; Ring, James H.; Ritchie, Franklyn; Roberts, Theodore; Robertson, Sir Johnson Forbes; Robson, Stuart; Rogers, Gus; Rogers, Max; Rooney, Pat; Ross, Charles J.; Rossi, Ernesto; Russell, Sol Smith
  - Cabinet cards, actors, S-T, V-W, 1875 -- 1915; MS003.001.015.001 (Box 15)
    Salvini, Alexander; Salvini, Tomasso; Sampolis, (?); Scott, Cyril; Serrano, Vincent; Sheridan, Richard B.; Sheridan, William E.; Shewell, Limington R.; Skinner, Otis; Smith, Edgar; Smith, H. Reeves; Sothern, Edward A.; Sothern, Edward H.; Sothill, John; Standing, Sir Guy; Stanley, Edward; Steger, Julius; Stevenson, Charles; Stewart, John S.; Stoddart, J. H.; Stone, Fred A.; Stone, Harry P.; Tabor, Robert; Taylor (?); Tearle, Osmund; Terriss, William; Thomas, Walter; Thompson, Denman; Thompson, WIlliam H.; Thorne, Charles, Jr.; Thorne, Tom; Tompkins, Orlando; Toole, John L.; Tree, Herbert (?); Vanderfelt, E. H.; Vaudenhoff, George; Vokes, Fawden; Warren, William; Walcot, Charles; Wallack, James W., Jr.; Wallack, Lester; Warfield, David; Weber, Joe; Webster, Ben; Weiser, Carl; Weston, Kendal; Wheatcroft, Nelson; Whelock, Joseph; Whitney, Myron; Whittlessey, White; Wilder, Marshall P.; Wilke, Hubert; Willard, Edward S.; Williams, Fritz; Williams, Gus; WIlson, Francic; Wilson, George W.; Wood, N. S.; Woodruff, Harry; Worthing, Frank; Wright, Fred, Jr.; Wyndham, Sir Charles
  - Cabinet cards, opera singers, men and women, A-Z, 1875 -- 1910; MS003.001.016.001 (Box 16)
    Male and female opera singers are alphabetized.
    Ackles, Arno; Albani, Emma; Alda, Frances; Aldwich, Mariska; Bartlett-Davies, Jessie; Besting, (?); Brema, Marie; Calve, Emma; Cary, Annie Louise; Clark, Abbie; Clemens Grabilowitsch, Clara; Corsi, Emilia; De Belocca, Anna; Delaro, Selina; De Lussan, Zelie; De Ronde (Delma?), Marie; Destin, Marie Louise; De Treville, Yvonne; Dow, Anna Granger; Eames, Emma; Fabris, Amanda; Farrar, Geraldine; Gadski, Johanna; Garden, Mary; Geister, Stelka; Geistinger, Marie; Hank, Minnie; Heilbron, Marie; Helena, Edith; Huntington, Agnes; Kellogg, Clara Louise; Kurz, Selma; Lehmann, Lilli; Lichtmay, Louise; Lucca, Pauline; Malavini, (?); Materna, Amalie; Maurer, Marie; Melba, Nellie; Nielson, Alice; Nilsson,Christine; Nordica, Lillian; Olitzki, Joe; Pappenheim, Eugenie; Parepa-Rosa, Euphrosyne; Patey, Janet M.; Patti, Amalia; Pearl, Clara; Perodi, (?); Remelsburg; Roze, Marie; Sacchetto, Rita; Salli-Curci, Amelita; Sembrich, Marcella; Scheff, Fritzi; Schilling, Mina; Schumann-Heink, Ernestine; Showalter, Edna; Smith, Charlotte; Sylva, Marguerita; Ternina, Milka; Torriani, Ostava; Van Studdiford, Grace; Van Zandt, Marie; Vix, Genvieve; Albani, Carlo; Amato, Pasquale; Bada, Angelo; Badini, Ernesto; Barelli, Luigi; Barnabee, Henry C.; Beckmans, M.; Berthald, Barron; Boudouresque (?); Caruso, Enrico; Chatterton, John (?); Constanino, Florencio; Cowles, Eugene; de Gorgoza, Emilio; Delmas, Jean-Francois; De Luca, Guiseppe; de Reszke, Edouard; de Reszke, Jean; Dyllyn, Bernard; Gilibert, Charles; Giraldoni, Eugenio; Henschel, SIr George; Lowell, Douglas; JSL (?); Maas, Joseph; MacDonald, William H.; Meyer, Ernest; Pasquales, Don; Paull, William; Pini-Corsi, Antonio; Plancon, Pol; Ritchie, Franklin; Rogers, Francis; Santley, Sir Charles; Scotti, Antonio; Sweatnam, WIllis P.; Toley, Allan James; Tomagno, Francesco; Tamberlink, Enrico; Tyler, Cyril; Vogl, Henrich; Wachtel, Theodor
  - Photographs, 5x7, opera singers, women, reprints of photos, 1855 -- 1930; MS003.001.017.001 (Box 17)
    All reprints from original negatives.
    Alten, Bella; Anegin, Sigrid; Von der Asten, Eva; Bellincioni, Gemma; Bori, Lucrezia; Brema, Marie; Breval, Lucienne; Brozia, Mme; Calve, Emma; Caron, Rose; Carre, Marguerite; Case, Anna; Cavalieri, Lina; Chenal, Marthe; Culp, Julia; Dal Monte, Toti; De Cisneros, Eleanora; Destinn, Emmy; Di Murska, Ilma; Eames, Emma; Easton, Florence; Engle, Marie; Fabbri, Guerrina; Fornia-Labey, Rita; Gadski, Joanna; Galli-Curci, Amelita; Galli-Marie, Marie Celestine; Garden, Mary; Gerville-Reache, Jeanne; Gerhardt, Elena; Hank, Minnie; Hampel, Freeda; Homer, Louise; Juch, Emma; Klafsky, Katharina; Kruszelnika, Salomea; Labia, Fausta; Lablache, Mme; Landouzy, Lise; Lehmann, Lilli; Lind, Jenny; de L'Isle, Marie; De Lussan, Zelie; de Macchi, Maria; Mantelli, Eugenia; McIntyre, Margaret; Melba, Nellie; Melis, Carmen; Michailowa, Marie; Mielke, Antonia; Olitzka, Rosa; de Pasquali, Bernice; Patti, Adelina; Rethburg, Elizabeth; Sack, Emma; Sanderson, Sybil; Schroder-Hanfstangel, Marie; Schumann-Heink, Ernestine; Seidl-Kraus, Auguste; Sembuch, Marcella; Stella, Antonietta; Storchio, Rosina; Sylva, Marguerita; Tetrazzini, Eva; Visconti, Raymonde; Wittich, Marie; Yaw, Ellen Beach
  - Photographs, 8x10, opera singers, women, A-L, autographed, 1923 -- 1970; MS003.001.018.001 (Box 18)
    All autographed, mostly to Henry Porter.
  - Photographs, 8x10, opera singers, women, M-W, autographed, 1923 -- 1970; MS003.001.019.001 (Box 19)
  - Photographs, 8x10, opera singers, men, A-W, autographed, 1927 -- 1971; MS003.001.020.001 (Box 20)
    All autographed, motsly to Henry Porter.
  - Photographs, 8x10, musicians, conductors and composers, men and women, 1903 -- 1982; MS003.001.021.001 (Box 21)
    All autographed, mostly to Henry Porter. Men and women alphabetized separately but placed in same box.